<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
	<id>com.jetbrains.PyCharm-Community</id>
	<metadata_license>CC-BY-SA</metadata_license>
	<name>PyCharm-Community</name>
	<summary>The most intelligent Python IDE</summary>
	<description>
		<p>PyCharm is designed by programmers, for programmers, to provide all the tools you need for productive Python development.</p>
		<p>PyCharm provides smart code completion, code inspections, on-the-fly error highlighting and quick-fixes, along with automated code refactorings and rich navigation capabilities.</p>
		<p>PyCharm offers great framework-specific support for modern web development frameworks such as Django, Flask, Google App Engine, Pyramid, and web2py.</p>
		<p>PyCharm integrates with IPython Notebook, has an interactive Python console, and supports Anaconda as well as multiple scientific packages including matplotlib and NumPy.</p>
		<p>In addition to Python, PyCharm supports JavaScript, CoffeeScript, TypeScript, Cython, SQL, HTML/CSS, template languages, AngularJS, Node.js, and more.</p>
		<p>A huge collection of tools out of the box: an integrated debugger and test runner; Python profiler; a built-in terminal; and integration with major VCS and built-in Database Tools.</p>
	</description>
	<url type="homepage">http://www.jetbrains.com/pycharm/</url>
	<url type="bugtracker">https://youtrack.jetbrains.com/</url>
	<url type="help">https://www.jetbrains.com/help/pycharm/</url>
	<launchable type="desktop-id">com.jetbrains.PyCharm-Community.desktop</launchable>
	<releases>
		<release version="2024.3" date="2024-11-13">
			<description></description>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.2.2" date="2024-09-19">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.2.1" date="2024-08-29">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.2.0.1" date="2024-08-20">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.2" date="2024-08-12">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.1.6" date="2024-08-09">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.1.5" date="2024-08-06">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.1.4" date="2024-06-25">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.1.3" date="2024-06-10">
			<description/>
		</release>
		<release version="2024.1.1" date="2024-04-30"/>
		<release version="2023.3.3" date="2024-01-26"/>
		<release version="2023.3.2" date="2023-12-20"/>
		<release version="2023.3.1" date="2023-12-12"/>
		<release version="2023.3" date="2023-12-06"/>
		<release version="2023.2.3" date="2023-10-12"/>
		<release version="2023.2.2" date="2023-10-02"/>
		<release version="2023.2.1" date="2023-08-24"/>
		<release version="2023.2" date="2023-07-26"/>
		<release version="2023.1.4" date="2023-07-13"/>
		<release version="2023.1" date="2023-03-30"/>
		<release version="2022.3.3" date="2023-03-09"/>
		<release version="2022.3.2" date="2023-01-26"/>
		<release version="2022.3.1" date="2022-12-28"/>
		<release version="2022.3" date="2022-12-01"/>
		<release version="2022.2.4" date="2022-11-17"/>
		<release version="2022.2.3" date="2022-10-11"/>
		<release version="2022.2.2" date="2022-09-15"/>
		<release version="2022.2.1" date="2022-08-17"/>
		<release version="2022.2" date="2022-07-28"/>
		<release version="2022.1.4" date="2022-07-21"/>
		<release version="2022.1.3" date="2022-06-22"/>
		<release version="2022.1.2" date="2022-06-01"/>
		<release version="2022.1.1" date="2022-05-12"/>
		<release version="2022.1" date="2022-04-13"/>
		<release version="2021.3.3" date="2022-03-17"/>
		<release version="2021.3.2" date="2022-01-28"/>
		<release version="2021.3.1" date="2021-12-29"/>
		<release version="2021.3" date="2021-12-01"/>
		<release version="2021.2.3" date="2021-10-20"/>
		<release version="2021.2.2" date="2021-09-15"/>
		<release version="2021.2.1" date="2021-08-27"/>
		<release version="2021.2" date="2021-07-28"/>
		<release version="2021.1.3" date="2021-06-30"/>
		<release version="2021.1.2" date="2021-06-02"/>
		<release version="2021.1.1" date="2021-04-22"/>
		<release version="2021.1" date="2021-04-07"/>
		<release version="2020.3.5" date="2021-03-26"/>
		<release version="2020.3.4" date="2021-03-17"/>
		<release version="2020.3.3" date="2021-01-27"/>
		<release version="2020.3.2" date="2020-12-30"/>
		<release version="2020.3.1" date="2020-12-21"/>
		<release version="2020.3" date="2020-12-02"/>
		<release version="2020.2.4" date="2020-11-27"/>
		<release version="2020.2.3" date="2020-10-07"/>
		<release version="2020.2.2" date="2020-09-17"/>
		<release version="2020.2.1" date="2020-08-26"/>
		<release version="2020.2" date="2020-07-29"/>
		<release version="2020.1.4" date="2020-07-22"/>
		<release version="2020.1.3" date="2020-07-08"/>
		<release version="2020.1.2" date="2020-06-03"/>
		<release version="2020.1.1" date="2020-05-07"/>
		<release version="2020.1" date="2020-04-08"/>
		<release version="2019.3.4" date="2020-03-18"/>
		<release version="2019.3.3" date="2020-02-07"/>
		<release version="2019.3.1" date="2019-12-19"/>
		<release version="2019.3" date="2019-12-02">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Interactive Widgets for Jupyter Notebooks. A picture is worth a thousand words, but making it interactive really makes your data come to life. Interactive widgets are now supported in PyCharm</li>
					<li>MongoDB Support. One of the most commonly used NoSQL databases is now supported by the database tools included in PyCharm Professional Edition</li>
					<li>We’ve completed support for all Python 3.8 features: you can now expect PyCharm-grade code completion when you use TypedDicts. We’ve also added support for Literal type annotations, and more</li>
					<li>Why is it that when you get a CSV file, it always has a very long name which is very prone to typos? We’ve now added a small convenience feature that’ll save you: completion for filenames in methods like open and Panda’s read_csv</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2019.2.5" date="2019-11-19">
			<description>
				<p>New in this Version:</p>
				<ul>
					<li>TypedDict support for Python 3.8</li>
				</ul>
				<p>Further Improvements:</p>
				<ul>
					<li>We’ve fixed and issue that caused the generation of a large skeleton file on remote interpreters</li>
					<li>The issue causing the Python plugin for IntelliJ not to work properly with the debugger when a tests Python module was created was solved</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2019.2.4" date="2019-11-01">
			<description>
				<p>Fixed in this Version:</p>
				<ul>
					<li>A regression issue that caused Pytest not to work properly with the debugger console was fixed</li>
					<li>The debugger console problem for PyQt5 that caused it to crash was solved</li>
					<li>We fixed an issue that was causing NumPy arrays not to be properly formatted in the Data View panel</li>
					<li>The IronPython problem causing the debugger to fail was fixed</li>
					<li>We took care of the debugger stack trace messages that are displayed when the debugger is stopped so they won’t show so you can properly know when the process was ended</li>
					<li>The regression issue causing the Pytest test suite to raise an error in PyCharm was solved</li>
				</ul>
				<p>Further Improvements:</p>
				<ul>
					<li>A platform issue that was modifying original file permissions upon saving them was solved</li>
					<li>We tweaked the error messages for SSH connections to show information properly</li>
					<li>Adding data source for databases via the explorer now opens directly the actual type of data source selected</li>
					<li>Completion for databases is now aware of the database or schema you’re currently working with so it will only show suggestions that belong to that context</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2019.2.3" date="2019-09-25">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>We solved an issue that was causing an error when invoking string literals</li>
					<li>Regression errors were fixed in the debugger</li>
					<li>The usage of multiprocessing on programs resulted on the inability to debug them and that was solved</li>
					<li>We fixed the issue that caused uncaught exceptions not to show traceback data</li>
					<li>Breakpoint usage while executing code in debug mode was causing different execution behaviors resulting in errors and that was fixed</li>
					<li>The problem causing Python interpreter not to be properly set if downloaded from the Windows Store was fixed</li>
					<li>The SVN performance was improved to avoid unnecessary processing of SVN operations’ results. Now projects with large amount of files using such version control system will experience enhanced processing times</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2019.2.2" date="2019-09-11">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Some code insight fixes were implemented for Python 3.8</li>
					<li>An error on the Python Console that was not showing documentation for functions was resolved</li>
					<li>Some issues were solved for IPython that were causing the debugger not to work properly</li>
					<li>We had some regression issues with the debugger causing breakpoints to be ignored and/or throw exceptions and the data viewer not to show the proper information and those were solved</li>
					<li>A problem that caused PyCharm to stall when a Docker server was configured as remote python interpreter was fixed</li>
					<li>An issue that was causing one remote interpreter not be used from two different machines was solved as well</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2019.2.1" date="2019-08-23">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>PyCharm now recognizes ctypes Arrays so now you won’t get wrong inspection messages when defining or using such arrays</li>
					<li>We had a bug that made Tensorflow’s references to be unresolved and that was also fixed</li>
					<li>An error displayed when trying to run Jupyter Notebook’ cells using managed and configured Jupyter servers that was not allowing Jupyter cells to run is now resolved</li>
					<li>We improved Jupyter’s server response error messages to be more user friendly</li>
					<li>A bug we had for imported names that was causing them to be imported again after inlining a function was fixed</li>
					<li>AltGr keymaps for certain characters that were not working are now fixed</li>
					<li>New SQL completion suggestions of join conditions based on column or table name match and auto-inject SQL by literals</li>
					<li>Some JavaScript and Vue.js inspection issues were resolved</li>
				</ul>
				The PyCharm debugger got some fixes:
				<ul>
					<li>The issue causing the debugger to hang when a syntax error was encountered was resolved</li>
					<li>When classes were given certain names, the debugger would be unable to inspect their variables, this is no longer a problem</li>
					<li>Exceptions thrown when debugging a project with multiprocessing modules will not stop the debugger anymore</li>
					<li>An issue that caused debugger functions like “Step into” to not work properly in our latest release was solved</li>
					<li>We had a bug that caused the debugger not to run normally when using Matplotlib and it was solved</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2019.2" date="2019-07-24">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Jupyter Notebook Integration has been improved. Some of the most highly requested Jupyter Notebook features have been implemented in this version. Now you will be able run all cells with a single button click, select and configure your Jupyter server using a specific project and port to listen to, keep track of variables while debugging them by getting their current state, restart the kernel and publish notebooks from PyCharm to JetBrains Datalore</li>
					<li>Syntax highlight support for many other languages has been added. Do you work on projects where code in a different language sneaks into your project? PyCharm will now highlight the syntax of Windows .bat files, C#, C++, Groovy, Lua, Makefiles, and more</li>
					<li>We are adding support for some major Python 3.8 features. Try out positional-only parameters, variable assignment within expressions, ‘Final’ qualifier to restrict usage of methods, classes and variables, and new ways to use f-strings to present values and variables</li>
					<li>cURL format is now supported for HTTP requests. Just copy your cURL formatted request and paste it directly into your HTTP Request file for it to be converted into its format, and then feel free to modify request params, headers, or body</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2019.1.3" date="2019-05-30"/>
		<release version="2019.1.2" date="2019-05-08"/>
		<release version="2019.1.1" date="2019-04-03">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>AltGr works correctly</li>
					<li>Previously, Python 3.8 pre-release interpreters were detected as Python 3.7, they’re now correctly identified as Python 3.8</li>
					<li>Various issues related to Conda environments have been fixed</li>
					<li>Some JavaScript and Angular inspection issues were resolved</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2019.1" date="2019-03-27">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Jupyter Notebooks support has been completely redesigned. Direct editing of Notebooks is now available in PyCharm 2019.1, with a convenient side-by-side view that helps you get a better overview of your Notebook’s source code while seeing the output right next to it. You can run and debug cells straight from the IDE.</li>
					<li>Quick documentation for HTML and CSS has been improved. Quick question: when writing a ‘padding’ property in CSS, what comes first? Left and right, or top and bottom? Just write ‘padding’ in a CSS file and press Ctrl-Q (or Ctrl-J on macOS) to find the answer!</li>
					<li>Navigate quickly to recent locations, rather than files. When you’re making quick edits, you frequently need to go back and forth between locations. The recent files popup (Ctrl-E, or Cmd-E on macOS) has always been there to quickly move between files you’re editing, but now we’ve also got the new and improved recent locations popup. Try it now: just press Ctrl-Shift-E (or Cmd-Shift-E on macOS).</li>
					<li>We’ve ending support for two Python versions: 2.6 (that has been end-of-life since 2013), and 3.4 (which just reached end-of-life). If you’re still using these versions, you’ll receive a warning that these versions are no longer supported. Some PyCharm functionality might no longer work, and we won’t fix any bugs related to these Python versions anymore.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2018.3.5" date="2019-02-27">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>If you have a private key with a passphrase, and would use to like native ssh rather than our built-in client for accessing remote git repositories, you’re now able to enter your passphrase in a dialog. This was previously only possible in combination with ssh-agent.</li>
					<li>The behavior of search everywhere was adjusted to rank partial filename matches higher in the results.</li>
					<li>The plugins redesign lead to issues with installing plugins offline. This has been resolved.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2018.3.4" date="2019-01-30">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Pasting a new name over a variable that was defined right after an indented block, would cause PyCharm to incorrectly indent the variable.</li>
					<li>In some cases inserting a newline in an f-string would lead to invalid code.</li>
					<li>PyCharm can now create Python 3.7 Conda environments</li>
					<li>Many improvements in SQL support. Did you know that PyCharm Professional Edition bundles all features from JetBrains DataGrip in its Database tool window?</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2018.3.3" date="2019-01-10">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>The debugger’s on-demand variable loading policy for NumPy arrays and Pandas DataFrames.</li>
					<li>File encoding specification inspection for Python 3.</li>
					<li>A fix for an extra __init__.py file created when moving a class into another module</li>
					<li>Several Docker and Docker Compose support fixes</li>
					<li>Fixes for embedded terminal</li>
					<li>Many fixes coming from WebStorm, DataGrip and IntelliJ IDEA</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2018.3.2" date="2018-12-19">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>PyCharm splits F-strings for you</li>
					<li>Clicking ‘View as DataFrame’ in the debugger would lead to an exception that is now fixed.</li>
					<li>Entering Hebrew text in the ‘Search Everywhere’ window would cause the IDE to hang. This has been resolved.</li>
					<li>An issue with MySQL handling NULL datetimes has been resolved.</li>
					<li>Many fixes coming from WebStorm, DataGrip and IntelliJ IDEA</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2018.3.1" date="2018-12-05">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>A fix for the recently added WSL support in PyCharm 2018.3</li>
					<li>An issue where PyCharm couldn’t correctly authenticate over SSH using a passphrase-protected private key has been resolved.</li>
					<li>A few fixes for Docker and Docker Compose</li>
					<li>Fixes for the embedded terminal</li>
					<li>Many fixes coming from WebStorm, DataGrip and IntelliJ IDEA</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2018.3" date="2018-11-21">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>For those of you on Windows who are developing applications that run on Linux: Windows Subsystem for Linux is a quick and easy way to always have a Linux environment available. PyCharm 2018.3 can now be configured to use a Python interpreter inside WSL.</li>
					<li>One of the most-requested features in our issue tracker were multiline TODOs, and we’re happy to announce that these are now available in PyCharm 2018.3.</li>
					<li>Even though search everywhere (double-shift) is not at all a new feature, we’ve made some great usability improvements, and now it’s easy to see how you can narrow down the results.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2018.2.5" date="2018-11-14">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>An issue that causes PyCharm to crash on Ubuntu 16.04 has been resolved</li>
					<li>Matplotlib 3.0.0 can now be imported in the Python Console</li>
					<li>Python code now folds correctly after it’s minimized with Ctrl+Shift+Numpad – (Cmd+Shift+- on macOS)</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2018.2.4" date="2018-09-21">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Various small pipenv improvements</li>
					<li>A bug in our pytest with fixtures support was fixed: previously, if yield statements were used in the fixture, PyCharm would assume that the return type of the function was a Generator. Now, the correct return type is inferred, preventing false positives.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2018.2.3" date="2018-09-06">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>A number of improvements and fixes for the integrated Python console</li>
					<li>Fixes for the new Quick Documentation window which was new in Pycharm 2018.2</li>
					<li>Fixes for few false positives: install an already existing package intention, type checks</li>
					<li>And much more, including improvements from the IntelliJ platform, WebStorm, and DataGrip, see the release notes for details.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2018.2.2" date="2018-08-21"/>
		<release version="2018.1.4" date="2018-06-10"/>
	</releases>
	<project_license>Apache-2.0</project_license>
	<developer_name>JetBrains s.r.o.</developer_name>
	<screenshots>
		<screenshot type="default">
			<image type="source">https://www.jetbrains.com/pycharm/img/screenshots/complexLook@2x.jpg</image>
		</screenshot>
		<screenshot>
			<image type="source">https://www.jetbrains.com/pycharm/img/screenshots/simpleLook@2x.jpg</image>
		</screenshot>
	</screenshots>
	<update_contact>sakcheen+flathub_AT_gmail.com</update_contact>
	<content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
</component>
