<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
	<id>com.jetbrains.PyCharm-Community</id>
	<metadata_license>CC-BY-SA</metadata_license>
	<name>PyCharm-Community</name>
	<summary>The most intelligent Python IDE</summary>
	<description>
		<p>PyCharm is designed by programmers, for programmers, to provide all the tools you need for productive Python development.</p>
		<p>PyCharm provides smart code completion, code inspections, on-the-fly error highlighting and quick-fixes, along with automated code refactorings and rich navigation capabilities.</p>
		<p>PyCharm offers great framework-specific support for modern web development frameworks such as Django, Flask, Google App Engine, Pyramid, and web2py.</p>
		<p>PyCharm integrates with IPython Notebook, has an interactive Python console, and supports Anaconda as well as multiple scientific packages including matplotlib and NumPy.</p>
		<p>In addition to Python, PyCharm supports JavaScript, CoffeeScript, TypeScript, Cython, SQL, HTML/CSS, template languages, AngularJS, Node.js, and more.</p>
		<p>A huge collection of tools out of the box: an integrated debugger and test runner; Python profiler; a built-in terminal; and integration with major VCS and built-in Database Tools.</p>
	</description>
	<url type="homepage">http://www.jetbrains.com/pycharm/</url>
	<url type="bugtracker">https://youtrack.jetbrains.com/</url>
	<url type="help">https://www.jetbrains.com/help/pycharm/</url>
	<launchable type="desktop-id">com.jetbrains.PyCharm-Community.desktop</launchable>
	<releases>
		<release version="2018.3.1" date="2018-12-05">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>A fix for the recently added WSL support in PyCharm 2018.3</li>
					<li>An issue where PyCharm couldn’t correctly authenticate over SSH using a passphrase-protected private key has been resolved.</li>
					<li>A few fixes for Docker and Docker Compose</li>
					<li>Fixes for the embedded terminal</li>
					<li>Many fixes coming from WebStorm, DataGrip and IntelliJ IDEA</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2018.3" date="2018-11-21">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>For those of you on Windows who are developing applications that run on Linux: Windows Subsystem for Linux is a quick and easy way to always have a Linux environment available. PyCharm 2018.3 can now be configured to use a Python interpreter inside WSL.</li>
					<li>One of the most-requested features in our issue tracker were multiline TODOs, and we’re happy to announce that these are now available in PyCharm 2018.3.</li>
					<li>Even though search everywhere (double-shift) is not at all a new feature, we’ve made some great usability improvements, and now it’s easy to see how you can narrow down the results.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2018.2.5" date="2018-11-14">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>An issue that causes PyCharm to crash on Ubuntu 16.04 has been resolved</li>
					<li>Matplotlib 3.0.0 can now be imported in the Python Console</li>
					<li>Python code now folds correctly after it’s minimized with Ctrl+Shift+Numpad – (Cmd+Shift+- on macOS)</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2018.2.4" date="2018-09-21">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>Various small pipenv improvements</li>
					<li>A bug in our pytest with fixtures support was fixed: previously, if yield statements were used in the fixture, PyCharm would assume that the return type of the function was a Generator. Now, the correct return type is inferred, preventing false positives.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2018.2.3" date="2018-09-06">
			<description>
				<ul>
					<li>A number of improvements and fixes for the integrated Python console</li>
					<li>Fixes for the new Quick Documentation window which was new in Pycharm 2018.2</li>
					<li>Fixes for few false positives: install an already existing package intention, type checks</li>
					<li>And much more, including improvements from the IntelliJ platform, WebStorm, and DataGrip, see the release notes for details.</li>
				</ul>
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="2018.2.2" date="2018-08-21" />
		<release version="2018.1.4" date="2018-06-10" />
	</releases>
	<project_license>Apache-2.0</project_license>
	<developer_name>JetBrains</developer_name>
	<screenshots>
		<screenshot type="default">
			<image type="source">https://www.jetbrains.com/pycharm/img/screenshots/complexLook@2x.jpg</image>
		</screenshot>
		<screenshot>
			<image type="source">https://www.jetbrains.com/pycharm/img/screenshots/simpleLook@2x.jpg</image>
		</screenshot>
	</screenshots>
	<update_contact>sakcheen+flathub_AT_gmail.com</update_contact>
	<content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
</component>
